Indiana History mss., 1725-1973 LMC 1544 LMC 1544
Lilly Library
- Indiana History
  - , William, 1866-1937, secretary to Pres. Theodore Roosevelt. The White House, Washington, D.C. To Addison Clay Harris, Fletcher's Bank Building, Indianapolis, Ind. On behalf of President thanks him for book., 1907, June 5 -; Typed Letter Signed 1 p. 23 cm. (Box 2)
    (Lilly Library F526.H33)
  - Steele, Theodore Clement, 1847-1926, artist. [Herman Lieber and His Influence upon the Art Development of Indianapolis]., 1908 -; Document 12 p. 21 cm. (Box 2)
  - Alexander, Mrs. Nellie (Sluss), fl. 1909. Paper read by Mrs. Nellie Sluss Alexander, February 19, 1909, presenting a Mexican War flag to the Monroe County Historical Society., 1909, Feb. 19 -; Autograph Document 2 p. 28 cm. (Box 2)
    A copy is filed with the flag in the Lincoln cupboard rare book department, Lilly Library. The flag was deposited in the Indiana University Library by the Monroe County Historical Society, February 6, 1934.
    The society made it a gift to the Library on May 7, 1948.
  - Turkey. Passport issued to John P. Leyendecker, fl. 1909, lawyer. Indianapolis, Ind., Document 1 p. 36 cm.; folio. (Box 5)
    Gift. Transferred from the Main Library. 1934-1936
  - Korbly, Charles Alexander, 1871-1937, congressman. Washington, D.C. To W. C. Engle, Indianapolis, Indiana. "Yours…in re the Telepost Bill received and contents noted…I am glad to have heard from you, and…I shall give this matter my very earnest consideration.", 1910, Mar. 9 -; Typed Letter Signed 1 p. 27 cm. (Box 2)
  - Cox, William Elijah, 1861-1942, congressman. Washington, D.C. To Frederick Pierce Leonard, Mt. Vernon, Indiana. "I will give the bill you write of careful consideration and if found in the interest of the masses you can rest assured I will support it.", 1910, Mar. 12 - (Box 2)
  - Cullop, William Allen, 1853-1927, congressman. Washington, D.C. To Frederick Pierce Leonard, Mt. Vernon, Indiana. "I am in receipt of your letter and will give the matter about which you write prompt attention.", 1910, Mar. 12 -; Typed Letter Signed 1 p. 27 cm. (Box 2)
  - Korbly, Charles Alexander, 1871-1927, congressman. Washington, D.C. To L. E. Dixon, Indianapolis, Indiana. "In the matter of the Telepost Bill…I wish to say that I shall give the same my support.", 1910, Mar. 22 -; Typed Letter Signed 1 p. 27 cm. (Box 2)
  - Woodburn, James Gelston, 1894-1980, professor. My Trip Abroad., 1911, July 20-1912, Sept. 23 -; Autograph Document Signed [423] pp. 22 cm. (Bound 45)
    1) presentation note from J. A. Woodburn to J. G. Woodburn, 1911, July 20 and 21
    2) title page
    3) log of the ship Menominee "outward bound" (the return voyage was on the Minnehaha)
    4) letter of James Albert Woodburn to James Gelston Woodburn, regarding his diary, his school in Berlin, and Bloomington as the center of population, signed "Papa," Sept. 5, 1911. (Autograph Letter Signed 6 pp. 21.5 cm)
    5) clipping regarding The Journal-Letter Home, Sept. 7, 1911, from Youth's Companion
    6) three typed notes for pages 46, 54, 82, dated 2-28-55.
  - Young Men's Christian Association of the State of Indiana. Subscription book., 1911, Oct. 31 -; Autograph Document [23] pp. 12 cm.; bound. (Box 4)
    Bound in maroon leather with organization's name in gold
    Contains names of subscribers, including those of L. S. Ayres & Co., C. B. Coleman, C. W. Fairbanks, J. K. Lilly, W. C. Marmon, David Ross, and W. N. Wishard, from several cities in the state for sums ranging from ten to one hundred dollars.
    Transferred from the files of Baker, Hord, and Hendricks mss. Small cases. Y.M.C.A. 1977
  - Nicholson, Meredith, 1866-1947, author. Indianapolis, Indiana. To Miss Eitel. "The sensation of having anybody invest in a volume of my jingles is a rare one.", 1911, Dec. 14 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 17 cm. (Box 4)
    Removed from Nicholson's Poems…Indianapolis, Bobbs-Merrill, 1906 (Lilly PR3527.I35 A17 Copy 1) 1964
  - Harding, George L. Scrapbook., 1912 - (Bound 46)
  - McCarthy, J. F., electro construction Co., electrical contractors, Arcade building, Philadephia, Pa. To the Hon. Rufus Magee, Daytona, Florida. Sending him a copy of Elbert Hubbard's John B. Stetson Aurora, N.Y., 1911, 1912, Mar. 18 -; Letter Signed 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 4)
  - Blumberg, Benjamin, 1889-1971, lawyer, financier, civic leader. Terre Haute, Indiana. Wills., 1912-1915 -; Autograph Document Signed [149] pp. 20.5 cm.; bound. (Bound 47)
    Reading notes concerning wills and legal provisions therefore, 1/2/12-3/17/12.
    Many notes on thin paper bound in.
    Pencil sketch of head on last page.
    Inscription dated: Jan. 13, 1915.
    On spine: Wills, and fragment of name…erg.
    Blumberg, born in Terre Haute, graduated from University of Chicago Law School in 1913 and practiced law in Terre Haute from 1913-1920.
    Gift. 1984
  - Biographical sketches of some prominent men living in Monroe and Lawrence Counties, Indiana., 1913, Sept. 10-Dec. 6 -; Typed Document 368 p. 36 cm. (Bound 48)
    With biographical revisions.
    100 sketches alphabetically arranged.
    Most of the sketches carry the signatures of the biographees on verso of last page.
    Printed in: History of Lawrence and Monroe Counties, Indiana, Their People, Industries and Institutions…Indianapolis, Ind., Bowen, 1914. pp. 461-764.
    Gift. Transferred from the Main Library. 1937
  - Farmers and mechanics' bank of Indiana, Madison. Articles of association, from manuscript copy of original found in bound volume of Madison Indiana Republican., 1913 -; Document 12 pp. 28 cm.; copy. (Box 4)
    Note at end: "Copied from the original manuscript thought to be in the handwriting of John Paul and now in the possession of Miss Drusilla Cravens of Madison Indiana. by Laura Esarey Jan. 8, 1913. The manuscript was neither signed nor dated."
    Transferred from the Main Library. 1919
  - Duss, John Samuel, 1860-1951, author. George Rapp and his associates (The Harmony Society). Address delivered…at the Centennial celebration at New Harmony, Indiana., 1914, June 6 -; Typed Document (carbon) 68 p. 23 cm. (Box 4)
    Published in Indianapolis, 1914 (Lilly HX656.H2 D76).
  - Hays, William Harrison, 1879-1954, lawyer, politician. Indianapolis, Indiana. To Logan Esarey, Bloomington, Indiana. Enclosing copies of such few publications of the Indiana Republican state committee issued during the campaign as are still on hand., 1914, Nov. 9 -; Letter Signed 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 4)
    Enclosures lacking.
  - Emerson, Frances E., Comp. Revolutionary soldiers buried in Indiana: [alphabetical biographical list, A-P]., 1915, Dec. 12 -; Typed Document 26 p. 22-28 cm. (Box 4)
  - Harrell, Mrs. Sarah (Carmichael), (Mrs. Samuel S. Harrell, 1844-1929, Jan. 24 teacher, writer. Brookville, Ind.) To Logan Esarey. Concerns a paper she wrote on Mary Louise Chitwood in 1912., 1916, Jan. 24 -; Autograph Letter Signed 6 p. 21 cm. (Box 4)
  - Lilly, Josiah Kirby, Jr., 1893-1966, corporation executive. Report on the Subject of Employment., 1916 -; Carbon on Typed Document [156] pp. 28 cm. (Box 4)
    Cover letter to Charles Jackson Flynn, 1874-1958, drug executive, dated Oct. 7, 1916, signed by J. K. Lilly, Jr., in pencil.
    Report made for the purpose of establishing an Employment Dept. for Eli Lilly & Co., Indianapolis, Indiana.
    Assisted by Dr. William Franklin Baker, 1883-1927, for the "medical side of Employment."
    Includes names of persons, companies, and agencies which provided information, bibliography, and forms used for data.
    Accompanied by xerox copy of two 3 x 5 cards, 1 p., 28 cm., which bear a quotation by J. K. Lilly, Sr., and J. K. Lilly, Jr. on the value of employees to a company.
  - Poucher, John., fl., 1917, clergyman. A religious survey of Orleans, Indiana: compilation of figures showing the sphere of the churches…, 1917, Feb. 26 -; Typed Document 6 p. 28 cm. (Box 4)
    Accompanied by a letter from John Poucher, Orleans, Indiana To Logan Esarey, Bloomington, Indiana, Feb. 26, 1917. (T.L.S. 1 p. 15cm).
  - Allen, C. T., lawyer. Waller Taylor: [a biographical sketch], 1917, June 13 -; Typed Document 3 p. 28 cm. (Box 4)
    Accompanied by a letter from C. T. Allen, Kenbridge, Va. To "My Dear Sir;" June 13, 1917. (Autograph Letter Signed 2 p. 14 cm.)
  - Miller, Augustus H., Nancy, and Thomas of Washington County, Ind., to Courtland ("Cort") Miller, 25 Jul. 1918-23 Aug. 1918 (Box 4)
    Purchased from Halvor Americana P.O. Box 221 Clarendon Hills, IL 60514 on 17 Apr. 2012 along with other items for $445
    Eight autographed letters to Courtland ("Cort") Miller from his father Augustus, mother Nancy, and brother Thomas, al datelined and/or on letterheads from Pekin, Indiana; consists of Augustus H. Miller, 25 July, 6 August, 16 August, 22 August, and 24 August 1918; Nancy Miller, 23 August 1918; Thomas Miller, 5 August and 12 August 1918; most with their original postmarked envelopes.
  - Miller, August H., 1860-1934, to Courtland ("Cort") Miller, 1891-1920, 29 Jul. 1918 - 24 Aug. 1918 (Box 4)
    Five envelopes (without letters) from August H. Miller to his son at Camp Taylor and Camp McClellan
  - Walker, Burke autograph letter signed ("Walker") on his Fowler, Indiana legal letterhead to "My Dear Cowern", 16 Feb. 1919 (Box 4)
  - Edna. Mooreville, Indiana. To Albert William Macy, 1750 Monadnock Building, Chicago, Ill. News of Roy and Pauline. "I bought this card of Old Jap Himself. He has a store in Brooklyn.", 1919, Mar. 28 -; Autograph Postcard Signed 9 cm. (Box 4)
    Verso of postcard pictures Jap Miller & Mr. Tug.
    Removed from Lilly Correspondence, Lilly Library, Indiana University. 1978
  - Indiana State Teachers' Association. William Taylor Scott, 1836-1918, in memoriam., 1919, Nov. 1 -; Typed Document 3 p. 28 cm. (Box 4)
  - Pleasant, Hazen Hayes, teacher. Maps of Crawford County, Ind., and a list of men who bought farms in Crawford County before 1818., 1920, Sept. 17 -; Autograph Document 8 p., including 5 maps. 28 cm. (Box 4)
    Prepared for his "A History of Crawford County," M.A. thesis, Indiana University, 1920.
  - Forty-two notes, papers and letters to Doyne Trout Koonce in answer to a request from her for information relating to the normal school movement in Indiana, for use in her master's essay on that subject, submitted to Indiana University in 1922., 1921, Dec. 6-1922, May 21 -; Document 68 p. 14-35 cm. (Box 4)
    Some of the letters are addressed to Logan Esarey.
  - Blythe, Arthur Raymond. Life of Jonathan Jennings., 1921 -; Document 92 p. 28 cm. (Box 4)
    Submitted as partial fulfillment of the requirements for the Master's degree in the Department of History at Indiana University, 1921. Rough typewritten draft with hand revisions. No pages numbered 16-20, 28-31, 36-39, 42-48, 50-51, 60-63, 67-77, 80-83, 85-94, 96-100, 102, 104, 106-107, 110-126, 129-130, 143.
  - Ku Klux Klan material, 1921-1932; Xeroxes of printed material (Box 4)
    De-accessioned from the Book Department, November, 1978
  - Nocktonick, Joseph, fl., 1922. Mayetta, Kansas. To James W. Lester, Gary, Ind. Gives data on various copy made from the original letters in the possession of Joseph Nocktonick, Mayetta, Kansas. Potawatomi Indians., 1922, Mar. 27-Apr. 14 -; Typed Letter, 2 items, 5 p. 28-33 cm. (Box 4)
  - Account of ceremonies at the unveiling of a tablet at the grave of Thomas Montgomery, ("Purty Old Tom Montgomery"), Gibson County, Ind., June 18, 1922., 1922, June 18 -; Autograph & Typed Document 52 pp. 10-28 cm. (Box 4)
    Contains speeches: 1) Zack T. Emerson, of Cynthiana, Ind. "The revolutionary soldier", pp. 21-27; 2) Mrs. Lewra (Montgomery) Simpson, "Purty Old Tom Montgomery", pp. 35-39.
  - Pauley, Edna E., fl. 1922. Pledge of loyalty, Queens of the Golden Mask., 1922, Oct. 18 -; Facsimile of Document Signed 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 4)
  - Stempfel, Theodore, 1863-1935, banker. To William Dudley Foulke, Richmond, Indiana. Refers to Foulke's Hoosier Autobiography and comments on the politics of World War I and the war work of the Quakers., 1923, Sept. 27 -; Typed Carbon Letter 3 p. 28 cm. (Box 4)
    Removed from William Dudley Foulke's A Hoosier Autobiography. New York, Oxford University Press, 1922. (Lilly E664.F75 H7). 1966
  - Foulke, William Dudley, 1848-1935, author. Richmond, Indiana. To Theodore Stempfel, Indianapolis, Indiana. Comments on condition of civil services and activities of the Ku Klux Klan., 1923, Oct. 2 -; Typed Letter Signed 3 p. 28 cm. (Box 4)
    Removed from Foulke's A Hoosier Autobiography. New York, Oxford University Press, 1922. (Lilly E664.F75 H7) 1966
  - Ray, Frederick Lucien, 1867-, mechanical engineer. Ray genealogy., 1924, Jan. 15 -; Document 1 p.; folio copy.; 34 x 52 cm. (Box 5)
    Photographic reproduction. Covering letter: Frederick Lucien Ray, Anderson, Ind. Apr. 5, 1924. To Logan Esarey, Bloomington, Ind. (Letter Signed 1 p. 28 cm).
    Gift. Letter accompanying says gift of Frederick L. Ray of the Union Traction Company of Indiana in Anderson, Indiana, on 9 Feb. 1924.
  - Stephenson, David Curtis, 1891-1966, klansman. To "Dear Sir." Is of the opinion that Ed Jackson would make a "real Governor of Indiana.", 1924, Apr. 10 -; Copy of Typed Letter 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 4)
  - Stephenson, David Curtis, 1891-1966, klansman. D. C. Stephenson, 304-5 Kresge Bldg., Indianapolis, Indiana. To "Dear Sir." Pleads for the nomination of Ed. Jackson for governor in the primary., 1924, Apr. 15 -; Typed Letter 1 p. 28 cm.; copy. (Box 4)
  - Lloyd's of London. All risks jewellery policy issued to Isaac and Ella Steiner, Indianapolis, Indiana., 1924, Aug. 6 -; Document 4 p. 41 cm.; folio. (Box 5)
  - Bossert, Walter F., klansman. To Officials…of the Ku Klux Klan in…Indiana. Deals with the propaganda waged against the Ku Klux Klan in Indiana., 1924, Oct. 20 -; Copy of Typed Document 4 p. 36 cm. (Box 4)
  - Monthly summaries of state funds: state of Indiana., 1924, Oct.-1933, Apr. -; Autograph Document pp. 8-29,; 40 x 47 cm. (Box 6)
    Cover title: Monthly summaries of state funds. State of Indiana, 1922.
  - Stephenson, David Curtis, 1891-1966, klansman. To "the Faithful Sons of Hoosierdom." "The Old Man's Answer to the Hate Venders.", 1924 -; Typed Letter 2 p. 36 cm.; copy. (Box 4)
  - Stephenson, David Curtis, 1891-1966, klansman. D. C. Stephenson, 304-5 Kresge Bldg., Indianapolis, Indiana. To David M. Hoover, Elkhart, Indiana. Hopes that Hoover will back a vigorous man for mayor in all towns and cities and win more honors for the Republican party., 1925, Mar. 7 -; Copy of Typed Letter 3 p. 36 cm. (Box 3)
    Accompanied by Hoover letter to Stephenson, Mar. 10, 1925. Indiana History mss.
  - Hoover, David M., fl. 1925, lawyer.; Law Office of David M. Hoover 309-310 Haynes Bldg., Elkhart, Indiana. To David Curtis Stephenson, 304-5 Kresge Building, Indianapolis, Indiana. Fails to find Stephenson's name connected with the Republican party and advises him to withdraw his "steadying" hand from the state of Indiana., 1925, Mar. 10 -; Copy of Typed Letter 3 p. 36 cm. (Box 3)
    Appended to Stephenson letter to Hoover, Mar. 7, 1925. Indiana History mss.
  - Hale, Will Taliaferro. To Truesdell, Frances Adrienne (Schmedel)., 1925, Dec. 17 (Box 3)
    Letter of Will T. Hale of Indiana University to Miss Schmedel thanking her for a gift, beginning: "It was certainly very kind of you to give me such an interesting Christmas present."
    Gift. 1982.
  - Hogston, Alfred. Local officers of the Ku Klux Klan in Indiana, 1925., Typed Document [carbon] 36 p. 33 cm. (Box 3)
  - Steele, Selma Neubacher, 1870-1945, educator. "House of the Singing Winds." To Paul Emerson Hamilton, 519 South Park Ave., Bloomington, Indiana. Welcomes the Cosmopolitan Club to visit the Studio Home and to have a picnic lunch on the grounds., 1927, May 9 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 20.2 cm. (Box 3)
    1) envelope with the return address of Mrs. T. C. Steele, R. 6, Bloomington
    2) unsigned copy in ink of Hamilton's letter to Mrs. Steele, May 1, 1927, accepting an invitation to visit the Studio, 28 cm.
    Gift. 1980
  - Nicholson, Meredith, 1866-1947, author. Golden Hill, Indianapolis, Indiana. To Margaret M. Scott. Will not speak at Christmas symposium; her writing., 1927, Nov. 6 -; Autograph Letter Signed 2 p. 17 cm. (Box 3)
    Removed from Nicholson's Poems … Indianapolis, Bobbs-Merrill, c. 1906 (Lilly PR3527.I35 A17 copy 1) 1964
  - Stephenson, David Curtis, 1891-1966, klansman. To Robert H. Moore, Michigan City, Indiana. "Please come out to see me.", 1927, Nov. 27 -; Facsimile of an Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 3)
  - Gresham, Otto, 1859-1946, lawyer, "In the sweat of thy brow shalt thou eat bread:" address prepared for the dedication of Michael Crawford Kerr's monument, 1928, May 25 -; Typed Document 35 p. 28 cm.; copy. (Box 3)
    Accompanied by photography of Michael Crawford Kerr and of newspaper clipping in the New Albany, Ind., Public Library entitled "Michael C. Kerr."
  - Polley, Frederick, 1875-, artist. New Orleans, La. To Mrs. Robert Elisha Burke, Bloomington, Ind. Tour of south; thanks her for invitation to visit Bloomington., 1929, Jan. 2 -; Letter Signed 2 p. 18 cm. (Box 3)
  - Salsbury, Elisa D., Indiana's Common School Fund., 1929, Jan. 10 -; Typed Document 35 p. 33 cm. (Box 3)
    Accompanied by carbon copy of covering letter from Elias D. Salesbury, to Roy P. Wisehart, state superintendent of public instruction, State House, Indianapolis, Ind. (3 p. 28 cm).
  - Feightner, Harold C., 1892-1969, executive, Stephenson case in brief. Deals with the murder of Madge Oberholtzer by David Curtis Stephenson., 1930 -; Typed Document 15 p. 28 cm. (Box 3)
  - Terre Haute, Indianapolis and Eastern Traction Co. Statistical data, prepared for Elmer W. Stout, receiver, by John O. Ryrholm, statistician. Covers Terre Haute, Indianapolis, and Eastern Traction Co., Terre Haute Traction and Light Co., and the following companies formerly operated under lease: Indianapolis & Northwestern Traction Co. (Northwestern division), Indianapolis & Martinsville Rapid Transit Co. (Martinsville division), and Indianapolis, Crawfordsville & Danville Electric Railway Co. (Crawfordsville division)., 1931, May 19 -; Typewritten. 16 p. 28 cm. map. (Box 3)
    [v. 1], Terre Haute, Indianapolis and Eastern Traction Co. (Brazil division, Danville division, and Eastern division).
    [v. 2], Terre Haute Traction and Light Co., Indianapolis and Northwestern Traction Co., Indianapolis, Crawfordsville and Danville Electric Railway Co., Indianapolis and Martinsville Rapid Transit Co.
  - Terre Haute, Indianapolis and Eastern Traction Company photographs, 19 May 1931 (Bound 49)
    Includes two volumes
  - Elmore, James Buchanan, 1857-1942, poet. Our life goes out as a shadow withdrawn., 1931, June 27 -; Autograph Document Signed 2 p. 27 cm. (Box 3)
    Signed "James B. Elmore, June 27, 1931 This is one of my latest poems …"
    Gift. Source unknown. 1934
  - Marion County, Ind.: Tables of County expenditures, 1926-1931, and appropriations, 1931-1932., Typed Document [4], 19 p.; 34 x 38 cm. (Bound 50)
    Cover title: Marion County, 1931. Mr. Miesse.
  - Green, James Albert, 1862-1955, civic leader. May 10-14, 1932, from Cincinnati to Chicago and return, via Peru, Terre Haute, Nashville, Indiana and Madison., 1932, May 10-14 -; Carbon of Typed Document Signed 33 p.; 23 cm. (Box 3)
    Autograph note on title page: "Presented to my friend, Arthur G. Mitten, by the author, James A. Green." Presented to Indiana University Library by Richard E. Banta, bookseller and publisher, Crawfordsville, Ind. 1946-1947
  - Sparks, William Tennis, 1849-1938, teacher. [Autobiography], 1932-1935 -; Autograph Document 5 vols. 24 cm. (Bound 51)
    Thomas Taggart, 1: 40
    Morgan's Raid in 1863, 1: 90-93
    passenger pigeons, 1: 199-200, 2: 1-2
    General Lafayette, 2: 86
    rail splitting, 2: 126-7
    memories of the Civil War, vol. 2
    and throughout frequent mention of books and literary interests, gardening, political rallies and elections.
    Gift. 1970
    Vol. 2 also has a biographical account of Uncle Johnny Walker, 1794-1878, drover, on pp. 3-34 and 154-163.
  - Collins, Grace Elizabeth Mitchell, 1896-1983, librarian. To Ernest Hiram Lindley, 1345 Louisiana Street, Lawrence, Kansas. Deals with information about the Lindley and Hollowell families., 1934, Apr. 26 -; Typed Letter (carbon) 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 3)
  - Lindley, Ernest Hiram, 1869-1940, university president. To Grace Elizabeth (Mitchell) Collins, 620 S. Woodlawn Avenue, Bloomington, Indiana. Comments on Lindley family, visit to Bloomington, and on son's publications., 1934, Apr. 30 - (Box 3)
  - Blankenship, Mrs. Minnie E. Paragon Literary Club, 1895-1933., 1934 -; Typed Document 5 p. 27 cm. (Bound 52)
    [1] Blankenship, M. E. To Wolf, Estella, Apr. 28, 1934
    [2] Typescript of Year Book, 1934-1935.
  - Hamilton, William James, 1884-, librarian. Early days in Merrillville, Lake County, Indiana, neighborhood: notes from 1935 prowlings., 1935, Oct. 14 -; Typed Document 8 p. 28 cm. (Box 3)
    1) Positive Photostat of five maps of area
    2) Photograph of Boyd-Saxton Wiggins pastureland, Sept., 1935.
  - Nicholson, Meredith, 1866-1947, author. Caracas, Venezuela. To Christopher Bush Coleman. Deals with Thomas A. Hendricks' religion and the antagonism between Walter Quintin Gresham and Benjamin Harrison., 1935, Nov. 26 -; Typed copy of Letter Signed 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 3)
  - Wilson, James Benjamin, 1859-1956, judge. To Newell Sanders, Chattanooga, Tennessee. Thanks Sanders for the gift of his biography which has caused him to live again the days of his boyhood and the "political side of American life" as he has seen it., 1936, Jan. 24 -; Carbon of Typed Letter Signed 2 pp. 28 cm. (Box 3)
    1) 4 letters from his wife, Maude E (Showers) Wilson, 1862-1938, July 22, 1936, mailed from Brooklyn, Indiana, and 1936[?], all of which request that the judge should bring some groceries from Bloomington
    2) printed campaign leaflet for James B. Wilson, Progressive nominee for Congress, 2nd District, Indiana, election, November 3, 1914.
    Gift. 1978
  - Carmichael, Hoagy, 1859-1956, pianist and composer. To To M. B. Yarling. Carmichael discusses his early career and the "swing frontier" in Indianapolis and Bloomington., 1936, November 12 -; Typed letter signed with handwritten postscript 5 pp. (Box 3)
    Includes envelope and photocopy of letter
    Purchase. 2014
  - Conlin, James W., teacher. The Merom Bluff Chautaqua., 1937 -; Typed Document 85 p. 28 cm. (Box 3)
    Table of contents
    prefatory material
    pt. I, History of the movement
    pt. II, Names of lecturers and dates of their appearance
    pt. III, Subjects discussed, name of speaker, and year address was delivered
    pt. IV, Names of entertainers and dates of their appearance
    pt. V, Musicians and musical organizations with dates of their appearance
    pt. VI, Titles of plays, names of producing companies, and dates of presentation
    pt. VII, Brief descriptions of talent which has appeared, 1905-1935
    pt. VIII, Stockholders
    pt. IX, Dates of the Merom Bluff Chautauqua
    pt. X, Platform managers
    pt. XI, Committees on transportation and buildings and grounds
    pt. XII, Program committees
    pt. XIII, Board of directors 2 drafts of pt. I
    Revised version of pt. I printed in Indiana Magazine of History, XXXVI: 23-28, March 1940. Accompanied by covering letters and correspondence of William O. Lynch, editor, Indiana Magazine of History, with the author.
  - Lockridge, Ross Franklin, 1877-1952, writer. Hoosier Historic Roadside Sites. Book II., 1938, Aug. 5 -; Typed Document Signed [2] p., p. 136-269. 28 cm. (Bound 53)
    Cover-title.
  - Skelcher, Mrs. Lucille Detraz, Vevay, Ind. Further notes on the descendants of the Dumonts., 1939, Feb. 16 -; Typed Document 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 3)